Rubin "Hurricane" Carter Papers MS226
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Correspondence, 1983 -- 2013; MS226.004; 7.2 Linear Feet
  - Personal correspondence (1 of 2), 1999 -- 2004; MS226.004.005.00039 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence (2 of 2), 1999 -- 2004; MS226.004.005.00040 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 2005; MS226.004.005.00041 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 2007 -- 2008; MS226.004.005.00042 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 2010 -- 2012; MS226.004.005.00043 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Telephone message book 9, 2008; MS226.004.005.00044 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Telephone message book 10, 2008 -- 2009; MS226.004.005.00045 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Telephone message book 11, 2009 -- 2010; MS226.004.005.00046 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Telephone message book 12, 2010 -- 2011; MS226.004.005.00047 (Box data_value_missing_1bf3371db5f8b81073905786da8bc3f8, Box 5)
  - Telephone message book 13, 2001 -- 2011; MS226.004.006.00001 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
- Court cases, 1989 -- 2014; MS226.005; 3.6 Linear Feet
  Court cases include legal documents, clippings, correspondence, fliers, memos, newsletters, notes, and other materials relating to cases in which Carter had an interest. Related files may also be found in series 8, subject files.
  Cases are organized alphabetically by name of defendant. There is also one related publication, filed by title.
  - Abu Jamal, Mumia (1 of 2), 2000; MS226.005.006.00002 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Abu Jamal, Mumia (2 of 2), 2000; MS226.005.006.00003 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Accornero, Roger, 2007 -- 2009; MS226.005.006.00004 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Allen, Jack E., 1999; MS226.005.006.00005 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Bjorge, Darcy Andrew, 1994; MS226.005.006.00006 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Boykin, Vonya, 2005; MS226.005.006.00007 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Bradford, Corey Chauncey, 2000; MS226.005.006.00008 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Brown, Joyce Ann, 2000 -- 2009; MS226.005.006.00009 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Cerra, Sebastian Peter, 2000; MS226.005.006.00010 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Collins, T. A., 1999; MS226.005.006.00011 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Cox, Tyrone Cory, 1998 -- 2000; MS226.005.006.00012 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Davenport, Thomas J., 2010 -- 2013; MS226.005.006.00013 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Doolin, Keith, 1998; MS226.005.006.00014 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Douglas, Willie, II, 2005; MS226.005.006.00015 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Downey, Gregory, 1995; MS226.005.006.00016 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Driskell, James, 1995; MS226.005.006.00017 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Erwin, Bonnie Burnette, 2005; MS226.005.006.00018 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Fabrikant, V. I., 1999; MS226.005.006.00019 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Faulder, Joseph Stanley, 1998; MS226.005.006.00020 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Fisher, Ronald Jerome, 2010; MS226.005.006.00021 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Gajka, Edward, 1997 -- 2005; MS226.005.006.00022 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Hart, Nelson Lloyd, 2012; MS226.005.006.00023 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Hope, William, 2000; MS226.005.006.00024 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Johnson, Jerome L., 2011; MS226.005.006.00025 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Johnson, Terrell, 2003; MS226.005.006.00026 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - LaGuer, Ben, 2011; MS226.005.006.00027 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Lapointe, Richard, 1993 -- 1994; MS226.005.006.00028 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - LaRue, Norman, 2014; MS226.005.006.00029 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Lawson, Charles (Zafir), 1999; MS226.005.006.00030 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Long, Ronald, 2000; MS226.005.006.00031 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - McCallum, David (1 of 3), 1989 -- 2014; MS226.005.006.00032 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - McCallum, David (2 of 3), 1989 -- 2014; MS226.005.006.00033 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - McCallum, David (3 of 3), 1989 -- 2014; MS226.005.006.00034 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Melendez, Juan Roberto, 2005; MS226.005.006.00035 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Middleton, David Stephen, 1999; MS226.005.006.00036 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Mitchell, Rollie Montez, 2014; MS226.005.006.00037 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Murray, Julian, 2014; MS226.005.006.00038 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Neal, Deyon, 2013; MS226.005.006.00039 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 6)
  - Peltier, Leonard, 1999 -- 2001; MS226.005.007.00001 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Rafay, Atif Ahmad and Glen Sebastian Burns, 2012; MS226.005.007.00002 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Redd Jr., Paul, 1998 -- 2004; MS226.005.007.00003 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Reasonover, Ellen, 2005; MS226.005.007.00004 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Reyes, Danny, 1998 -- 2005; MS226.005.007.00005 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Roberts, Wayne, 2000; MS226.005.007.00006 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Santiago, Wilfred, 2003; MS226.005.007.00007 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Shaw, Jeff, 2013; MS226.005.007.00008 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Smith, Eric, 1992; MS226.005.007.00009 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Smith, Gregory L., 2012; MS226.005.007.00010 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Spirko, John, 2005; MS226.005.007.00011 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Steigl, Gordon Randy, 1995; MS226.005.007.00012 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Taylor, Christopher, 2010; MS226.005.007.00013 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Thomas, Larry D., 2013; MS226.005.007.00014 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Trafficking in Persons Report, 2003; MS226.005.007.00015 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Vanderburg, Randy, 2000; MS226.005.007.00016 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Walker Jr., John H., 2005; MS226.005.007.00017 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Williams, Lester Leroy, 2011; MS226.005.007.00018 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Willoughby, Danny, 2000 -- 2013; MS226.005.007.00019 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Young, Donzel, 1994 -- 1995; MS226.005.007.00020 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Yurko, Alan, 1999; MS226.005.007.00021 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
- Photographs, 1950 -- 2012; MS226.006; 3.6 Linear Feet; 6 Digital Object(s)
  Photographs consist mainly of images of Carter with his friends, family, and colleagues. Photographs also document Carter's homes, vacations, and events at which he appeared. There are a few photographs of Carter with well-known figures such as Nelson Mandela, Denzel Washington, and Norman Jewison, and with exonerated prisoners. There are both prints and negatives in this series.
  Photographs are arranged alphabetically.
  - Bertha Carter, 90th birthday party, 1999; MS226.006.013.00001 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Bob Dylan Review, New York, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00002 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter, 1950 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00003 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
    - Rubin Carter, boxing promotional photograph, 1950 -- 1969; MS226.006.013.00003.00001 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
      Boxing; photographic prints; Carter, Rubin, 1937-2014
    - Rubin Carter, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00003.00002 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
      photographic prints; Carter, Rubin, 1937-2014
    - Rubin Carter in his doctoral regalia, receiving an honorary doctorate from Griffith University, 2003; MS226.006.013.00003.00003 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
      Australia; Honorary degrees; photographic prints; Carter, Rubin, 1937-2014; Griffith University
  - Carter and David Millgaard conference, 1990 -- 2000; MS226.006.013.00004 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carther and others at the JCC Sports Dinner, 1999; MS226.006.013.00005 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter and Ron Dalton, 2008 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00006 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter and the family, 1996; MS226.006.013.00007 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at an unidentified event, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00008 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at the Griffith University honorary doctorate conferral ceremony (1 of 4), 2003; MS226.006.013.00009 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at the Griffith University honorary doctorate conferral ceremony (2 of 4), 2003; MS226.006.013.00010 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at the Griffith University honorary doctorate conferral ceremony (3 of 4), 2003; MS226.006.013.00011 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at the Griffith University honorary doctorate conferral ceremony (4 of 4), 2003; MS226.006.013.00012 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter at Sacred Heart University, Fairfield, Connecticut, 2000 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00013 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter, Bill Dukes, Lilee Anderson, and Sam, 2000 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00014 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter, Cousin George, and Mike, 1990 -- 1999; MS226.006.013.00015 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter headshots, 1999; MS226.006.013.00016 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
    - Rubin Carter, headshot, 1999; MS226.006.013.00016.00001 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter in Mexico, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00017 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter in South Jersey, with correspondence, 1966; MS226.006.013.00018 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter, John Mazzilotti, Perri, and Augie, 1996; MS226.006.013.00019 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter, Johnny Cochran, Denzel Washington, Terisa, Griffith University, Carter's 60th birthday, Mike and Carol Ann Lethen, 1997 -- 2001; MS226.006.013.00020 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter on fishing trips, 1995 -- 1999; MS226.006.013.00021 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter on vacation, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00022 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter on vacation with unidentified people, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00023 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter outside with film crew, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00024 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter outdoors with unidentified people, 1980 -- 1989; MS226.006.013.00025 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter signing programs and books, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00026 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter snapshots, boxing matches, and portraits, 1960 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00027 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter vs. Gomeo Brennan, 1960 -- 1969; MS226.006.013.00028 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with Denzel Washington, 1999; MS226.006.013.00029 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with Linda Thompson, 1990 -- 1999; MS226.006.013.00030 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with John Artis and others, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00031 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
    - Lesra Martin, John Artis, Rubin Carter, Denzel Washington, and Cheryl Martin, 1999; MS226.006.013.00031.00001 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
      photographic prints; Carter, Rubin, 1937-2014; Martin, Lesra, 1963-; Artis, John; Washington, Denzel, 1954-; Martin, Cheryl
  - Carter with Nelson Mandela, 2000; MS226.006.013.00032 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
    photographic prints; Carter, Rubin, 1937-2014; Mandela, Nelson, 1918-2013
  - Carter with Norman Jewison, 1999; MS226.006.013.00033 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with Norman Jewison and others, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00034 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with Rick King, 2000; MS226.006.013.00035 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with unidentified people, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00036 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Carter with unidentified people and studio portrait of an unidentified woman, 2002; MS226.006.013.00037 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Craig Smyth photography, photocopies of 1950s-1960s boxing photographs, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00038 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - David Baine in prison in New Zealand, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00039 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Denzel Washington in The Hurricane, 1998; MS226.006.013.00040 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Denzel Washington with Carter's family, 1999; MS226.006.013.00041 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Denzel Washington with Carter's family and Norman Jewison ephemera, 1995 -- 1999; MS226.006.013.00042 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Inscribed photographs, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00043 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Inside 155 Delaware Ave., 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00044 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Kay - Ron Dalton, pictures sent to speakers, 1965 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00045 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Personal pictures - Kerr, Larry, Gwyn, and David McCillan, past female friends, and Rubin in England, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00046 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Possible pictures for speakers?, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00047 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Rally for Carter with Muhammad Ali, 1974; MS226.006.013.00048 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Rolando Cruz on Death Row and at Boxing Hall of Fame, with others, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00049 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Ron and Tommy Parks, 1994; MS226.006.013.00050 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Rubin Carter at work and play, 1980 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00051 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Sounds Like Justice event, exterior and interior of 155 Delaware Ave, and Carter with unidentified people, 2000 -- 2001; MS226.006.013.00052 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Sounds Like Justice photos, Carter (Maurice) being freed, graduation at Griffith University, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00053 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Swainsboro, Georgia Community Center, 1980 -- 1999; MS226.006.013.00054 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Sylvester Stallone and unidentified man, 2000; MS226.006.013.00055 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Teresa and her family in Toronto, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00056 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Unidentified boxing match, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00057 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Unidentified negatives, 1990 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00058 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Unidentified people and house, 2012; MS226.006.013.00059 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - Unidentified people and places, 1980 -- 2009; MS226.006.013.00060 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - The Way Community Center, Swainsboro, Georgia and Niagara Falls, 2000; MS226.006.013.00061 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
  - York University, Fall Convocation, 2005; MS226.006.013.00062 (Box data_value_missing_4f0696a6584067640774aa28075aa367, Box 13)
- Printed materials, 1967 -- 2004; MS226.007; 3.6 Linear Feet
  Printed materials include reprints and books sent as gifts to Carter, and often inscribed.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Bjorklund, Lorence F. Faces of the Frontier, inscribed copy, 1967 -- 2004; MS226.007.007.00022 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Bright, Stephen B. and Patrick J. Keenan. Judges and the Politics of Death: Deciding Between the Bill of Rights and the Next Election in Capital Cases, 1995; MS226.007.007.00023 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Carter, Rubin. Keynote address in Santa Clara Law Review, Vol. 35, no. 2, 1995; MS226.007.007.00024 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Chaiton, Sam and Terry Swinton. Lazarus and the Hurricane sample book jacket, 2000; MS226.007.007.00025 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Morris, Ruth. How Do We Convince the Public? The Place of Community Education in Creating Healing Justice, 2004; MS226.007.007.00026 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - The Champion, 1999; MS226.007.007.00027 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Goodman, John and Pete Hamill. The Times Square Gym, inscribed copy, 1996 -- 1999; MS226.007.007.00028 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Hirsch, James S. Hurricane sample book jacket, 2000; MS226.007.007.00029 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
- Subject files, 1950 -- 2012; MS226.008; 10.8 Linear Feet
  Subject files contain materials on a wide range of topics, in varying formats. Major subjects include Carter's work at the Association in Defense of the Wrongly Convicted (AIDWYC) and other organizations with which he was affiliated, speaking engagements and business ventures, prisoners in whose cases Carter was interested, and information on legal cases. Formats include clippings, correspondence, legal documents, memos, reports, agendas, minutes, notes, and reprints. Topics in this series overlap with materials in series 2. business and financial records, series 5. court cases, and series 10, writings.
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 1994 -- 2011; MS226.008.007.00030 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC, 1995; MS226.008.007.00031 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC agenda, correspondence, and memos, 2000 -- 2003; MS226.008.007.00032 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC agenda, correspondence, and memos, 2001; MS226.008.007.00033 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC conference, 2002 -- 2003; MS226.008.007.00034 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC constitution and bylaws, 1995 -- 2001; MS226.008.007.00035 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC journal, 1995 -- 2003; MS226.008.007.00036 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC memos and correspondence, 2004; MS226.008.007.00037 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC November conference, 2000 -- 2004; MS226.008.007.00038 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC pamphlets - Unlock the Truth, 2001 -- 2003; MS226.008.007.00039 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC proposal - justice code, 2004; MS226.008.007.00040 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC resignation, 2004; MS226.008.007.00041 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC Sounds Like Justice benefit concert, 2001; MS226.008.007.00042 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - AIDWYC telephone list and memos, 2003 -- 2004; MS226.008.007.00043 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Australia - Griffith University Innocence Project, 2003; MS226.008.007.00044 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - Bates, Chris - affidavit, 2001; MS226.008.007.00045 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
  - BBC - Liza radio interview, 2001; MS226.008.007.00046 (Box data_value_missing_d37076278a65a68b627f92b3b37669f8, Box 7)
    Audiocassette removed to box 16.